Guide to the World War I Posters File [1914]-1920 PR 55-7
New-York Historical Society
- Series III: Patriotic Appeals, 3
  - Subseries III.1: Patriotic Appeals to Workers, Farmers, Miners etc., 16
    - Community Service News / The "New Mexico" Buries her head under a / Mountain of water / Keep the Glad hand for the fighting man (Folder 20)
    - W.B. Wilson, Secretary of Labor Says We are proceeding by/Evolution not by/Revolution (Folder 20)
      photo of Secretary Wilson
    - "Nothing but harmony, honesty, industry and frugality are necessary to make us a great and happy people" George Washington in a letter to Lafayette./It is not the followers of false gods who are the true benefactors of labor, but those who... (Folder 20)
    - Making America better/Somewhere back down the way we have travelled lies/The safe road to a better/America. Frederick H. Giletter, Speaker of the U.S. House of Representatives (Folder 20)
    - The past is behind us/The future is ahead/Let us all strive to/Make the future/Better and brighter/Than the past ever was, 1918 (Folder 20)
      soldier and farmer shaking hands
    - "I shall expect every man who is not a / Slacker to be at my side throughtout this / Great enterprise." Woodrow Wilson to all employees / This plant is executing a contract for the US Navy (Folder 20)
      Liberty leading the way
    - Proclamation / State of New York. Executive Chamber / ..Waste helps only our enemy. Protect our / Supplies and help with the war / Charles S. Whitman (Gov.); William A. Orr (Secretary to Gov.), 1917-07-17 (Folder 20)
    - Don't carry a / Chip on / Your shoulder / There's a knocker / For every chip. / Terence V. Powderly / Chief Division of Information / Bureau of Immigration / Dept. of Labor (Folder 20)
    - You and your job / After the war / Working men of America Consider where you will stand when the war is / Ended! Then the time of your big opportunity to lay by something for a rainy / Day will have passed. (Folder 20)
    - What doth it profit a man? / Stand by you work for your own honor and safety / For the safety and success of your fellow countrymen.. (Folder 20)
    - To the miner let me say that he stands wehre the Farmer does; the work of the world watis on him. If he slacks for fails armies and statesmen are helpless. He also is enlisted in the greate service army. (signed) Woodrow Wilson, 1917 (Folder 21)
      Flag / US Capitol
    - You are needed to help build ships / The Pacific Coast offers good wages and conditions / American ships will win the war (Folder 21)
    - Dr. Uncle Sam / is now in charge of our industrial troubles. / He has prescribed a Victory Tonic called Cooperation. / Cooperation will win the war., 1918 (Folder 21)
      Cartoon: Wage earner / wage player in sick bed being fed co-operation tonic by Uncle Sam
    - Proclamation for the Industrial Peace / By the President Woodrow Wilson / Robert Lansing, Secretary of State, Members of the National War Labor Board / There should be no strikes during the war (Folder 21)
      Uncle Sam uniting worker and employer shaking hands
    - Appeal by Belgian workmen, 1918-03-03 (Folder 21)
      Belgian subjects being attcked and "herded up" slave labor deportation by German soldiers
    - Team Work / It ain't the individual or the Army / As a whole, / But the everlasting team work / of every bloomin' soul. / Kipling (Folder 21)
      Hunitions workers making arms for soldiers in the field (rear)
    - Farm help / Do you need help now? / You must make your labor needs known at once / Don't count your laborer until he is hired / How many extra hands at harvest? (Folder 21)
    - Farming problems in 1919 / Appeal to direct attention to the necessity of counting our state of preparedness and of strenghtening the foundations of our agriculture / D. Houston (& seal of Dept of Agriculture), 1918-11-13 (Folder 21)
      photo of Houston
    - Let the work that you do every day be dedicated to (list of German atrocoties) / Issued by Conference Committee on National Preparedness, Metropolitan Life Bldg / Madison Ave. NYC / Harry A. Wisewood, Chairman, Raymond B. Price, Treausurer, James C. .. .. (Folder 21)
    - Pershing says: "I want the s.o.s. to know how the first Army appreciates the prompt response made to every demand for more equipmnet, supplies and transportation necessary to carry out the receht operations." The s.o.s. shares success with us. (Folder 21)
      Portrait bust of Pershing
    - Go over the top with the tank that will win the war / "Kan the Kaiser", 1918 (Folder 21)
      Cartoon of wage earner / wage payer atop attacking tank labeled: "American Industry / Co-operation"
    - Presiden't Wilson's great message / Read at the joint session of the Congress / At Washington, April 2, 1917 (Folder 21)
      Photo of Wilson
    - Baby's prayer at twilight / "Won't you help bring my Daddy home?" (Folder 21)
      baby crying / battleships at sea
    - Department of Labor / US Public Service Reserve / If you can use tools, you are needed / For patriotic service at good wages to / Build ships. The following list shows the kinds of trades most needed in ship building. (Folder 21)
    - Volunteers wanted for farm work / Will you help for a season or longer? / A place will be found fro you / Your country needs you! / Will you serve on the farms? / W.B. Wilson, Sectretary of Labor (Folder 21)
      A farmer and Uncle Sam who says, "I'll bring the boys back to the farm for you."
  - Subseries III.2: Appeals from Civilan Associations in Connecticut, Minnesota, Missouri, and Pennsylvania, 17
    - "Victory" war rally / Branford Armory, Branford, March 27, 1918, at 8 pm. (Folder 22)
    - War rally / Under auspices of Conn State Council of Defense / Boys in France stand for America; / Come out and line up behind them (Folder 22)
      soldiers in battlefield (in silhouette)
    - "Return Load" / This Map shows how Connecticut truck oweners and shippers are increasing transporation faculties / use motor trucks to relieve local terminal congestion (Folder 22)
      map of Conn
    - Order concerning nonwar construction / War industries board / Washington DC, 1918-10-01 (Folder 22)
    - Let us "Highly resolve that these dead whall not have died in vain. / Burial of American soldier victims of Tuscania sinking / February 5, 1918 / 101 brave Americans lost their lives (Folder 22)
      4 photos of funeral scenes for victims
    - It pays to stay in school / a trained worker's advantage in earning power / an untrained worker's slow rise in life (Folder 22)
      a pictoral graph
    - Connecticut State Council of Defense / Committee of Food Supply / Save wheat / Save meat / Save fats / Save sugar / Use perishables / Use local supplies (Folder 22)
    - If you need farm labor, ask for it / the farmer can get labor (Folder 22)
    - Send Sammy Smilage $1.00 / Patriotic stores sell "Smileage books" / Let your soldier see camp shows as your guest / send him a "Smileage." (Folder 22)
    - Men and women / do you have to change your job? / If so / consult Uncle Sam the US employment service will place you without charge (Folder 22)
    - Boys and Girls! / A million dollars worth of food has been sent as the goal for the / Junior Food Army in Connecticut / Join the Junior Food Army (Folder 22)
    - Why Germany wants peace now / Kaiser's "Intrigue for peace" a menace to America and the world (Folder 22)
      map of Europe stamped "the Prussian Blot"
    - The world can not live half slave, half free / While Germany dreams of dominating the world by force there can be no peace (Folder 22)
    - If you need farm labor / Ask for it (Folder 22)
    - Kaiser Bill / Maybe you didn't know it before, but I'm telling you now / US means Unconditional Surrender / Uncle Sam (Folder 22)
      hand of Uncle Sam signing his name
    - Fighting in France for freedom! Are you helping at home? News Photo poster #6: 70,000 patriotic and loyal women marched in NY for Red Cross Fund / The American Red Cross needs another Hundred Million dollars to "carry on." "War fund week" May 20 27 (Folder 22)
      Nurses and other women parading E 40th St and 5th (?) Ave
    - Farmers of Connecticut / Farmers of Mass Meeting / To be held in the House of Representatives at the State Capitol, Friday, Mar 22 at 11AM / Consider the present emergency (Folder 22)
    - The 10 Commandments of womanhood / 1918 / Prepared by the President of the Conn Congress of Mohters (Folder 22)
    - Missouri leads for food increases, 1918 (Folder 22)
      Father plowing / men fighting and graph of food increase
    - Why we are at war? / .. .. That is what this war means / If we are beaten, what have we a right to expect? (Folder 22)
    - Serve to win without a gun / Wear this button / It means you have joined the US Public Service Reseserve (Folder 22)
      button of US PSR
    - Honor roll of women who will work to win the war / has he registered your name for service? (Folder 22)
      Uncle sam listing names on blackboard
    - Mothers / Fathers / Public service needs your boys / Enroll them for nonmilitary emergency work in the Pennsylvania Division / US Boys Working Reserve / Let them fill the gaps in our industry (Folder 22)
    - Latest official USA and British war films / Sergent Arthur Gibbons of Canada's first thirty thousand / A prisoner of war at Giessen Camp, Germany / An intense, forceful speaker / Don't miss story he will tell at Sanford School Gymnasium, April 4 AT 5PM (Folder 22)
      Serbent Gibbons
    - Fighting in France for freedom! Are you helping at home? News Photo Poster #20: The Soldiers Hustling when the call comes "All Hands to the guns, here comes an aeroplane" (Folder 22)
      English town running to their posts
    - Fighting in France for Freedom! Are you helping at home? News Photo poster #2: An american dugout / holding the Lorraine trenches (Folder 22)
      Soldiers on the front line of Allied western front
    - Germans / You must register / Between Monday Feb 4 and Saturday Feb. 9 / Present yourself early before the postmaster (same message in German) (Folder 22)
    - The War at home / School boys of Connecticut / Help the Farmers witht their harvest Join the US Boy's working reserve and Jr. Agricultural Volunteers (Folder 22)
      boys helping plow the fields, harvest
    - Fighting in France for freedom! Are you helping at home? News photo poster #23: "Force without stint" and larger Guns will proabably be US answer to Austrias Peace Negotiations (Folder 22)
      Long 16 inch gun to be shipped overseas with 19 men standing on top
    - Fighting in France for Freedom! Are you helping at home? News Photo poster #13: Greatst of all parades demonstrate that America is acting as one in this war (Folder 22)
      Fourth of July parade in NYC where over 75,000 people paraded
    - Fighting in France for freedom! Are you helping at home? News Photo poster #12: Work or Fight / What's the difference between a slacker and a traitor? / Think it over. (Folder 22)
      A striking scene when the French charged the Germans and put them to rout
    - Fighting in France for freedom! Are you helping at home? News Photo poster #11: In the trenches behind the lines in France (Folder 22)
      African-American soldiers / white commander firing from the trenches
    - Fighting in France for freedom! Are you helping at home? News Photo poster #10: The alarm has been sounded and the Marines are adjusting thir masks and entering their dugouts W.S.S. enlistment day will be June 28. (Folder 22)
      American marines entering dugouts when gas attack is on.
    - Fighting in France for freedom! Are you helping at home? News Photo poster #9: Soldiers in France resting and sleeping in the trenches while a bombardment is going on / Beware of spies and enemy eavesdroppers! (Folder 22)
      Soldiers sleeping in trench during attack
    - Fighting in France for freedom! Are you helping at home? News Photo poster #8: Boys getting accustomed to gas drills before they leave for over there. / Be prepared for national W.S.S. enlistment day / Friday, June 28th. (Folder 22)
      Boys in midst of Gas defense drill at Yapahanic, L.I.
    - A message to the men and women of Connecticut Franklin D. Roosevelt, Assistant Secretary of the Navy (Folder 22)
      FDR
    - Fighting in France for freedom! Are you helping at home? News Photo poster #7: A striking scene in the allies army in front of Amiens / Friday, June 28th National War Savings Enlistment Day (Folder 22)
      An 18 pounder battery with its crew of men with gas masks stemming a German advance
    - Your President and your Governor endorse the Children's Year / What will you do to save 1056 babies in Connecticut in 1918? (Folder 22)
    - Justice but no flowers (Folder 22)
    - America Calls for Nurses enroll / An appeal to women of Connecticut / Conn Committee for the Recruiting of Student Nurses (Folder 22)
      nurse
    - Support our soldiers / by shopping sensibly / purhcase useful gifts only / and make this a winthewar Christmas (Folder 22)
    - Beware of Spies / and enemy eavesdroppers / Keep you eyes and ears open / Report eveyr suspicious act / Or word to the Connecticut Council of Defense, State Capitol, Hartford, Conn / Keep your mouth closed (Folder 22)
    - President Wilson's message to the boys of Pennsylvania / United States boy's working reserve (Folder 22)
    - Fighting in France for Freedom! Are you helping at home? News Photo poster #5: Typical scene abroad whe soldiers are being nursed back to health (Folder 22)
      Casualties of the battles on Picardy front in hospital beds on convalescent ward
    - Get behind / the girl he left behind him / Join the land army / Become a supporting member / Membership classes / Tiller $1.00 / Planter $5.00 / Gleaner $25.00 / Harvester $100.00 (Folder 23)
      Woman with hoe infield (in colour); fighting soldier in background (grey)
  - Subseries III.3: Civilian War Work (Womens work, Womens Land Reserve, Boys Working Reserve), 18
    - "Eternal vigilance is the price of Liberty" / American Defense Society / Vigilance Corps, 1919 (Folder 23)
      man on look out atop NY building; NY skycscraper scene rear
    - Register / For Woman's Work / Your country needs you / November 9th 27th, 1917-08-01 (?) (Folder 23)
      Liberty with arm on civilian woman; flag near
    - Your Country Needs You / Young Women needed now / to train as nurses / in the military and / civil hospitals / of the United States / For information apply to / Miss Hellen Wood, Central Recruiting Station, Massachusetts (Folder 23)
      General Hospital, Boston
    - Stage Women's War Relief (Folder 23)
      Woman shedding fancy fur trimmed coat to reveal hurses uniform, hands reaching out
    - Fight world famine / Enroll in the Boys' Working Reserve / US Employment serve / Departement of Labor (Folder 23)
      Boy on farm being attacked by vultures
    - Farm for freedom / Young men of America / Between 16 and 21 years / Earn a badge of honor / Join the US Boys' Working Reserve / Apply / or write US Boys' Working Reserve, Washington DC (Folder 23)
    - Boys! Serve your country on the farms / Join the US Boys' Working Reserve / Apply / Earn a badge of honor (Folder 23)
      Farm Scene / logo of Boys' Working Reserve, USA
    - The Woman's Land Army of America / Women enlist now and help the farmer /fight the food famine / Apply National Office, 19 West 44th ST, NY State office, 303 Fifth Ave, 1918 (Folder 23)
      3 Women doing farm work; one carries a flag
    - Women awake! Your country needs you / Learn to be of National Service Join the Navy League / Help the Navy Local Headquarters (Folder 23)
      woman in uniform with megaphone or horn
    - Service / Fall in! / National League for Women's Service (Folder 23)
      Women in uniform on horse carryng US flag leading horde of women carrying rakes, canned goods, books, etc.
    - Community Councils of National Defense / We serve (Folder 23)
      seal with eagle and motto
    - Civilian(s*) / When we go through this we need all the help and combat you can give / the Jewish Welfare Board / United War Work Campaign Week of November 11, 1918 (Folder 23)
      soldier in combat; Jewish Star
  - Subseries III.4: Miscellaneous Patriotic Appeals, 19
    - Waiting for a job, sir / At the Reemployment Bureau / for soldiers, sailors, marines / 505 Pearl St. Phone Worth 9250 / Send him a job / Major Warren Bigelow, USA, Director / Thinnk thousands gave lives you can give work (Folder 24)
      Soldier, sailor saluting
    - Warning / Lie / Rumor / (List of) the rumor / The fact / Don't let the Germans fool you with their lies / Do your part / Report the names of persons circulating such rumors to Natl Committee of Patriotic Societies, Southern Bldg, Washington DC (Folder 24)
      Dog labeled rumor with tin can labeled "lie" tied to his tail
    - Don't talk / The web is spun for you with invisible threads / Spies are listening (Folder 24)
      Man's head caught in a spiderweb
    - Harmless! / This is not a joke, but a stern reality / Copies may be obtained from the (sic) Business men's National Service League, 96 Water Street, NYC, 1917 (Folder 24)
      Cartoon: German soldier laughing at cannon labeleld "Volunteer System"
    - The US Government / Has asked us to help / .. .. .. Will you please / Shop in the moning hours / Avoid making hurried purchases / Avoid special delieveries / Delivery and distribution waste must be eliminated, 1917 (Folder 24)
    - No war talk! / Attorney General Gregory says: / "Obey the law / Keep your mough shut!" (Folder 24)
    - To all aliens / If the war has affected your living or working conditions / If you want to learn the American language and become a citizen .. .. .. Apply Room 1820 Minicipal Building (Folder 24)
      Same message in German, Polish, Hungarian, Yiddish, Italian
    - Patriotic League / I pledge to express my patriotism by doing better than ever before whatever work I have to do, 1918 (Folder 24)
      Woman, american flag, patriotic league pledge
    - The world cannot live half slave, half free / While Germany dreams of dominating the world by force there can be no peace (Folder 24)
      Map of Europe with Germany expanding in red; The "Prussian Blot"
    - Proclamation! / To the citizens of New York / Mitchel, Mayor (Folder 24)
      Proclomation declaring US entry to WWI
    - The Harriman National Bank / urges / faith, courage, and patience, 1918 (Folder 25)
      various war scenes; face of man looming above with red / white stripes radiating from horizon
    - Celeberate Don't miss the parade. / Show the boys you're / for them in Victory as in the war / Celebrate (Folder 25)
      Victory parade of US soldiers
    - This beautiful / Picture for framing / Free / Free/ Free / Printed on heavy glazed paper / See daily New York Herald, Page 2, part 1, 1918 (Folder 25)
      Prtrait bust of Gen. John J. Pershing
    - I have a boy / By Daniel M. Henderson / Author of the National Art Club's $250 Prize War Poem, "The Road to France" (Folder 25)
      Soldier with binoculars agains various flags and text of poem
    - The right is more precious than Peace / We shall fight for the things we have always carried nearest to our hearts / The world must be made safe for democracy. / Woodrow Wilson (Folder 25)
      Photo of Wilson in oval frame
- Series IV: Conservation Appeals, 4
  Series IV: Conservation Appeals, includes posters encouraging citizens to conserve food, fuel, and other supplies for the war effort. Posters relating to Daylight Savings Time are included.
  - Subseries IV.1: US Fuel Administration and Misc. Fuel Conservation, 20
    - Save fuel in dairy plants / Nearly onehalf the coal can be saved / Study your plant / Save the fuel (Folder 26)
    - Stand by the boys in the trenches / Mine more coal, 1918 (Folder 26)
      Soldier and miner shoulder to shoulder
    - Jan. 30th / Tag / your shovel / day / Has your Coal Shovel / been tagged yet? (Folder 26)
      Shovel with tag "Save that shovelful of coal a day for Uncle Sam"
    - Uncle Sam says: / "Stop Sunday joyriding / and put the skids under / the Kaiser." / Save gasoline! / Sacrifice for Liberty! / Hit the Hun on high gear! (Folder 26)
    - Order your coal / now / Get it out of / Uncle Sam's way / he needs / the railways / for war (Folder 26)
      Hand with shovelful of coal and slogan "Save that shovelful" (US Fuel Administration logo)
    - Save your coal / to fire the Kaiser / Here's how… / Thomas W. Russell, Commecticut Fuel Administration (Folder 26)
      Uncle Sam and coal worker
    - Mine more coal / Stand by the boys in the trenchs! (same message in Italian, Polish, Hungarian, German) (Folder 26)
      US eagle
    - Uncle Sam / needs that / extra shovelful (Folder 26)
      Uncle Sam with arm on man stoking furnace with coal
  - Subseries IV.2: Food Conservation; US Food Administration, 21
    - The Spirit of '18 / The world cry / Food / Keep the home garden going, 1918 (Folder 27)
      Farmers carrying produce / wheat
    - Feed a fighter / Eat only what you need / Waste nothing / That he and his family / may have enough (Folder 27)
      Soldier in trench holding cup and saucer
    - Food is / Ammunition / Don't waste it (Folder 27)
      Basket of fruit, vegetables, soldiers in background
    - Food will win the war / You came here seeking freedom / You must now help to preserve it / Wheat is needed for the allies / Waste nothing (Folder 27)
      Immigrants arriving past Statue of Liberty
    - Save the / products of the land / Eat more fish / they feed themselves (Folder 27)
      Fish swimming underwater
    - Keep it coming / "We must not only / feed our soldiers / at the front / but the millions of / women and children / behind our lines" Gen John J. Pershing (Folder 27)
      Truckloads of food coming to the front
    - Blood or bread / Others are iving their blood / You will shorten the war / Save life if you eat only what / you need, and waste nothing (Folder 27)
      Worker holding dead soldier
    - Food and the war! / American wheat to win! / Wheat is the test! (Folder 27)
    - This is / what God gives us / What are you giving / So that others may live? / Eat less / Wheat / Meat / Fats / Sugar / Send more to Europe / or they will starve (Folder 27)
      Fruit, vegetables, nuts surrounding message
    - War / Rages in France / We must feed them / they cannot / fight and raise / food at the same time / denying our / selves only a / littl means / life to them (Folder 27)
      War -torn village scene of civilians fleeing bombed town (printed from woodcut?)
    - Sir / Don't waste while / Your wife saves / Adopt the doctrine / of the clean plate (Folder 27)
      Prosperous man at restaurant with food left on plate while he lights up a cigar, appaled waiters in background
    - Save / 1. Wheat / Use more corn / 2. Meat / Use more fish and beans / 3. Fats / Use just enough / 4. Sugar / Use syrups / and serve the cause of freedom (Folder 27)
    - L'Italia / Ha Bisogono / di Carnefrumento grasso e zucchero (Folder 27)
      Head of Italian soldier
    - Why / loyal Americans are keeping the pledge / to eat less wheat and meat (Folder 27)
    - Don't waste food / While others starve (Folder 27)
      Emaciated mother and chldren before bombed out church
    - Eat more / Corn, oats and rye / Products fish / And poultry fruits vegetables and potatoes / baked boiled and broiled fods / leat less / wheat, meat, sugar and fats / to save for the army / and our allies (Folder 27)
      Table with fish, fruit, vegetables
    - Food / 1. Buy it with thought / 2. Cook it with care / 3. Use less wheat and meat / 4. Buy local foods / 5. Serve just enough / 6. Use what is left / Don't waste it (Folder 27)
    - Kosciuszko / Pulawski (Folder 27)
      Portrait of Koscwszka